to disrupt the agricultural food desert and begin to correct the dysfunctional food system that we've created. So maybe it seems like a really small countermeasure to a big, huge problem -- just go plant flowers -- but when bees have access to good nutrition, we have access to good nutrition through their pollination services. And when bees have access to good nutrition, they're better able to engage their own natural defenses, their healthcare, that they have relied on for millions of years. So the beauty of helping bees this way, for me, is that every one of us needs to behave a little bit more like a bee society, an insect society, where each of our individual actions can contribute to a grand solution, an emergent property, that's much greater than the mere sum of our individual actions. So let the small act of planting flowers and keeping them free of pesticides be the driver of large-scale change. On behalf of the bees, thank you. (Applause) Chris Anderson: Thank you. Just a quick question. The latest numbers on the die-off of bees, is there any sign of things bottoming out? What's your hope/depression level on this? Maria Spivak: Yeah. At least in the United States, an average of 30 percent of all bee hives are lost every winter. About 20 years ago, we were at a 15-percent loss. So it's getting precarious. CA: That's not 30 percent a year, that's -- MS: Yes, thirty percent a year. CA: Thirty percent a year. MS: But then beekeepers are able to divide their colonies and so they can maintain the same number, they can recuperate some of their loss. We're kind of at a tipping point. We can't really afford to lose that many more. We need to be really appreciative of all the beekeepers out there. Plant flowers. CA: Thank you. (Applause)
para interrumpir el desierto agroalimentario y comenzar a corregir el sistema alimenticio disfuncional que hemos creado. Tal vez parezca una muy pequeña contramedida para un grave, enorme problema - solo se trata de plantar flores - pero si las abejas tienen acceso a buena nutrición, nosotros también tendremos buena nutrición gracias a sus servicios de polinización. Y cuando las abejas tienen acceso a buena nutrición, son más capaces de utilizar sus propias defensas naturales, su sistema de salud, en el que han confiado durante millones de años. Así que la belleza de ayudar a las abejas de esta manera, para mí, es que cada uno de nosotros se comporte un poco más como una sociedad de abejas, una sociedad de insectos, donde cada una de nuestras acciones individuales pueda contribuir a una solución magnífica, una propiedad emergente, que es mucho mayor que la simple suma de nuestras acciones individuales. Hagan que el pequeño acto de plantar flores y mantenerlas libres de pesticidas, sea el motor de un cambio a gran escala. En nombre de las abejas, gracias. (Aplausos) Chris Anderson: Gracias. Sólo una pregunta rápida. Los últimos números de la mortandad de las abejas, ¿hay alguna señal de que las cosas estén tocando fondo? ¿Cuál es tu nivel de esperanza o depresión en esto? Maria Spivak: Sí. Por lo menos en los Estados Unidos un promedio del 30 % de todas las colmenas de abejas se pierden todos los inviernos. Hace unos 20 años, estábamos en una pérdida de 15 %. Así que cada vez es más precaria. CA: No es el 30 % anual. MS: Sí, 30 % anual. CA: 30 % anual. MS: Pero los apicultores pueden dividir sus colonias y pueden mantener el mismo número, pueden recuperar algunas de sus pérdidas. Estamos en un punto de inflexión. No podemos darnos el lujo de perder mucho más. Tenemos que estar muy agradecidos de todos los apicultores que hay. Planten flores. CA: Gracias. (Aplausos)